Curriculum Vitae

Steven Marcel Bißantz

Nordparkstraße 10b, 76829 Landau +49 1525 3606062

bissantz@uni-landau.de

https://github.com/sbissantz

DOCTORAL RESEARCH

Measurement & Replicability in the Sciences - Meta-Scientific Investigations in The Role of Measurement in The Replicability of Empirical Findings

My research concentrates on the role of measurement in replicability. In particular, the focus is on how (a) modifying validated item-based measurements or (b) the practice of tossing various items together in a "scale" (i.e., omitting the validation process) affects the replicative success of a study. Despite the replicative success, I illuminate the influence of these ad-hoc and post-hoc scales on effect size estimates and their induced heterogeneity.

WORK EXPERIENCE

CURRENT, FROM OCT 2021
(PROF. DR. EUNIKE WETZEL)

University of Koblenz-Landau PhD Student, Psychology

Mainly, I am involved in meta-science; learn about quantitative methods, and teach test theory, diagnostics, and R.

MAY 2019 – JUL 2021

(ZEPF)

Centre of Educational Research Research Assistent, Psychology

I researched mode effects in performance tests (VERA) using structural equation models and multilevel modeling.

SEP 2016 – APR 2018 (PROF. DR. IRENA KOGAN)

University of Mannheim Research Assistent, Sociology

Data analysis, literature research, and the administration of the internet presence in English and German were among my tasks.

University of Mannheim (PROF. DR. FRANK KALTER)

Research Assistent, Sociology

As a tutor, I reviewed the course material content, clarified unanswered questions, and deepened the understanding of my fellow students in complementary teaching sessions.

APR 2015 - JUL 2015

Mannheim Centre for European Social Research
Research Assistent, Sociology

After theoretical and practical training, I conducted computer-assisted telephone interviews (CATI).

MEMBERSHIPS

CURRENT, FROM FEB 2021

University of Koblenz-Landau

Member of the Open Science Comission

At the OSC we promote the implementation of open science practices.

EDUCATION

2019-2021 **M. A. Social Science** (1,0)

Department of Social Sciences
University of Koblenz-Landau

2018-2019 Survey Statistics

Department of Economics University of Bamberg

2014-2018 B. A. Sociology (1,6)

Department of Sociology University of Mannheim

PUBLICATIONS

Bißantz, S. (2021). *elisr*: Exploratory Likert Scaling in R. R package version 0.2.0. https://CRAN.R-project.org/package=elisr

Wagner, I., Loesche, P. & **Bißantz**, **S.** (2021). Low-stakes performance testing in Germany by the VERA assessment: analysis of the mode effects between computer-based testing and paper-pencil testing. European Journal of Psychology of Education. 10.1007/s10212021-00532-6

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2021 (WS)	Test theory & Diagnostics	(exercise)
2022 (SS)	Data analysis in R	(EXERCISE)
2022 (SS)	Test theory & Diagnostics	(SEMINAR)

COMPUTER SKILLS

OPERATING SYSTEMS Linux, macOS & Windows
LINUX DISTRIBUTIONS Fedora, openSUSE & Arch
STATISTICAL SOFTWARE R, Stan, Stata & SPSS
MISCELLANEOUS Git, Vim & Emacs

Proficiency: Server administrator in our working group "Personality, Psychological Assessment, and Psychological Methods" at the University of Koblenz-Landau

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Meta Science What is the effect of scale modifications on inferences, replicability and effect-size heterogeneity?

Bayesian Data Analysis How to maximize information entropy using Bayesian updating?

Maschine Learning How to minimize cross-entropy in prediction tasks?